[MUSIC]
[음악]
Let's train the sentiment classifier.
감성 분류기 훈련시키기
And we're gonna do this in two steps.
두 단계로 나눠서 진행합니다
First, we're gonna do a train test split of the data.
먼저 데이터를 훈련/테스트 세트로 나눕니다
So I'm gonna compute the training data.
훈련 데이터를 계산,
We're gonna split the data into training data.
아니 나눕니다
And test data just like we talked in the regression class and
테스트 데이터는 회귀 강의에서 보고
just like we did in the regression notebook.
회귀 노트북에서 한 것과 같습니다
So we're gonna use, we'll take this product table.
상품 표를 사용합니다
Products.
상품
And then we're going to do the random split.
그다음 랜덤 스플릿을 합니다
So, oops.
아
Products.
상품
And then we're gonna do that random split,
그다음 랜덤 스플릿을 훈련 80에 테스트 20으로
where we're gonna do 80% for training, 20% for testing.
합니다
And just so that you can reproduce this at home, I'm gonna do the seed = 0.
다시 재현해볼 수 있게 시드는 0으로 줍니다
Just like we discussed in regression.
회귀에서 했던 방식이지요
Normally you wouldn't do this, you pick another random seed, but
원래라면 이렇게 안하고 랜덤 시드를 고르겠지만
I wanted the random seed to be the same,
지금은 같은 시드를 씀으로써
so when you do it, you get exactly the same results I did.
강의와 같은 결과를 얻는 게 목적입니다
So this is my first step, train test split on this data set, and now we're ready.
훈련, 테스트 데이터 세트를 나누는 게 첫 단계고
We're gonna build that famous sentiment model.
다음으로 감성 모델을 만듭니다
And here, we're going to use graphlab and
graphlab과 로지스틱 분류기란
we're going to use a particular classifier called the logistic classifier.
분류기를 사용합니다
And in the course on classification,
분류 강의에서
we're going to learn a lot about different kinds of classifiers like logistic
로지스틱 회귀, 서포트 벡터 머신, 결정 트리 등을
regression, this one, support vector machines Decision trees and others.
배우게 됩니다
But let's start with just a logistic classifier.
로지스틱 분류기로 시작하죠
And just like in you can type .create after the name and
이름 뒤에 .create을 붙이면
it'll actually create the classifier for you.
분류기를 생성해 줍니다
And as input, it takes us a few parameters.
입력으로 몇 가지 파라미터를 받습니다
So we're gonna take the train data, as one parameter.
훈련 데이터가 그중 하나입니다
Then we're gonna see that the target,
그리고 분류하고자 하는 대상은
the thing we're trying to classify, is the sentiment column.
감성 열입니다
And then we're gonna have to tell it what features to use.
특징을 지정합니다
So for the features we're going to use just the word count column.
특징으로 단어수 열을 씁니다
So this is the new column that we've created above for word count.
단어수를 저장하기 위해 생성했던 열입니다
And, I'm going to give that a validation set.
검증 세트를 줍니다
So the validation set is going to be my test_data.
검증 세트는 test_data가 됩니다
So validation_set=test_data.
validate_set=test_data지요
Okay.
좋아요.
So now we execute the cell.
칸을 실행합니다
And we shall be a building a sentiment classifier model.
감성 분류기 모델이 만들어집니다
And we're only gonna take a few seconds, and here we go.
몇 초쯤 걸립니다
It's done.
다 됐네요
And you will see [INAUDIBLE] the data, and
반복을 하면 할수록
the validation accuracy as it goes along it seems to be getting better and better.
검증 정확도가 점점 나아지네요
But let's actually do a peer evaluation.
그래도 실제 평가를 한번 해보죠
[MUSIC]
[음악]